Mss.B.W564
American Philosophical Society
- II. University of Texas Correspondence and Files, 1976-2006 (Box 34-71)
  - University of Colorado, Boulder, 1977-1979 (Box 67)
    Brittin, Wesley
  - University of Delaware, 1984 (Box 67)
  - University of Kansas, 1985-1986 (Box 67)
  - University of Louisville, 1978-1980 (Box 67)
  - University of Minnesota, 1979 (Box 67)
  - University of Newcastle Upon Tyne, 1983 (Box 67)
  - University of North Carolina, 1976-1977 (Box 67)
  - University of Oklahoma, 1976 (Box 67)
  - University of Pittsburgh, 1980 (Box 67)
  - University of South Florida, 1984 (Box 67)
  - University of Southern California, 1980 (Box 67)
  - University of Texas. The Ex-Students' Association, 1985-1986 (Box 67)
  - University of Texas at Austin, 1976-1988; 3.0 folders (Box 67)
    - Folder #1, 1976-1986 (Box 67)
      Flawn, Peter T. (1983); Lieb, Irwin C. (1978-1979). -- See also Series II: American Association of University Women
    - Folder #2, 1978-1988 (Box 67)
    - Folder #3, 1977-1987 (Box 67)
  - University of Texas at Austin. College of Natural Sciences., 1982-1993 (Box 67)
  - University of Texas at Austin. Department of Physics, 1976-1986; 5.0 folders (Box 67)
    -- See also Series II: Walther, Herbert
    - Folder #1, 1976-1979 (Box 67)
    - Folder #2, 1980-1985 (Box 67)
    - Folder #3, 1984-1986 (Box 67)
    - Folder #4. PHY 341: Great Men, Great Moments, Great Ideas, 1982 (Box 67)
    - Folder #5. John A. Wheeler Graduate Fellowship in Physics, 1986 (Box 67)
  - University of Texas at Austin. Humanities Research Center, 1978-1979, n.d. (Box 68)
  - University of Texas at Austin. Office of the President, 1987-2006 (Box 68)
  - University of Texas at San Antonio, 1986 (Box 68)
  - University of Texas Press, 1978 (Box 68)
    Kyle, John H.
  - University of Texas System. Office of the Chancellor, 1987-1996 (Box 68)
  - University of Uppsala, 1977 (Box 68)
    Calais, Jean-Louis; Goscinski, Osvaldo; Lowdin, Per-Olov
  - University of Wyoming. Archive of Contemporary History, 1979 (Box 68)
  - Unruh, William George, 1976-1987; 2.0 folders (Box 68)
    -- See also Series II: Narlikar, Jayant V.; Sigma Xi
    - Folder #1, 1976-1981 (Box 68)
    - Folder #2, 1982-1987 (Box 68)
  - Unz, Ron K., 1983 (Box 68)
  - Vajk, J. Peter, 1976-1977 (Box 68)
  - Valanju, Alaka, 1977-1980 (Box 68)
  - Vance, Cyrus, 1979 (Box 68)
  - Vandenbosch, Robert, 1978 (Box 68)
  - van der Laan, Harry, 1977 (Box 68)
  - van Fraassen, Bas C., 1977-1985 (Box 68)
    Sorabji, Richard (1985)
  - van Hove, Leon, 1980-1983 (Box 68)
  - Van Kranendonk, Jan, 1978-1984 (Box 68)
    Desai, Rashmi; Noolandi, Jan; Sipe, John
  - van Nieuwenhuizen, Peter, 1980-1981 (Box 68)
  - van Thiel, A[rnoud], 1977 (Box 68)
  - Van Vleck, John H., 1978-1980 (Box 68)
  - Venkatasubramanian, V., 1978 (Box 68)
  - Vera, Eduardo, 1981 (Box 68)
  - Victoria, Ulises E., 1980-1985 (Box 68)
  - Friedr. Vieweg und Sohn, 1985 (Box 68)
  - Vilenkin, Alexander V., 1976-1979 (Box 68)
  - Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, 1977 (Box 68)
  - Visions of Einstein Media, 1985 (Box 68)
  - Vogt, Robert C., 1977 (Box 68)
  - Volkoff, George M., 1983-1986 (Box 68)
  - von Koller, Otto, 1979 (Box 68)
  - von Weizsacker, Carl Friedrich, 1977-1986 (Box 68)
    MIT Press (1980). -- See also Series II: Ravindra, Ravi
  - Wagner, Siegfried, 1980 (Box 68)
  - Wahsner, Renate, 1979-1980 (Box 68)
  - Wakano, Masami, 1977-1988 (Box 68)
    -- See also Series II: Sigma Xi
  - Wald, Robert M., 1978-1985 (Box 68)
  - Walker, Evan Harris, 1986 (Box 68)
  - Wall, Frederick T., 1986 (Box 68)
  - Wallace, Bryan G., 1981-1985 (Box 68)
  - Wallace, John, 1976-1978 (Box 68)
  - Waller, Sergio M., 1980 (Box 68)
  - Walter Murray Collegiate Institute, 1979-1980 (Box 68)
  - Walther, Herbert, 1986-1988 (Box 68)
    University of Texas at Austin. Department of Physics
  - Wang, Frank, 1979 (Box 68)
  - Wang, Hao, 1985 (Box 68)
  - Warner, Ogden M., 1976 (Box 68)
  - Warren, Mashuri L., 1977 (Box 68)
  - Washington State University, 1979 (Box 68)
  - Washington University (St. Louis, Missouri), 1985 (Box 68)
  - Watson, Thomas J., Jr., 1982 (Box 68)
  - Way, Katharine, 1978-1983 (Box 68)
  - Weaver, Jefferson, 1983-1987 (Box 69)
    American Scholar
  - Weber, Alfred H., 1978 (Box 69)
  - Weber, Joseph, 1976-1986 (Box 69)
  - Wehr, Marco, 1987 (Box 69)
  - Weinberg, Alvin M., 1978-1986 (Box 69)
    Motz, Henry
  - Weinberg, Steven, 1978-[1987] (Box 69)
    Cushing, James T. (1985); Weinberg, Louise
  - Weiner, Joseph S., 1976-1977 (Box 69)
  - Weintraub, Sidney, 1978 (Box 69)
  - Weismann, Donald L., 1978 (Box 69)
    Smith, Gerald
  - Weiss, Richard A., 1977-1979 (Box 69)
  - Weisskopf, Victor F., 1979-1986 (Box 69)
    Zichichi, Antonino. -- See also Series II: Sarfatti, Jack (1977, 1980); Union of Concerned Scientists
  - [Wellner], Marcel, 1977 (Box 69)
    -- See also Series II: Greenberg, [Oscar] Wallace (Sept. 1977)
  - Weltman, I., 1978 (Box 69)
  - Werner, Frederick [G.], 1980 (Box 69)
  - Wetzels, Walter D., 1979 (Box 69)
  - Weyl, Michael, 1985-1987 (Box 69)
  - Wheaton, Bruce R., 1977, 1983 (Box 69)
  - Wheeler, John Craig, 1977-1987 (Box 69)
    -- See also Series II: Ehlers, Jurgen
  - Wheeler, John McGehee, 1987 (Box 69)
  - White, Karl, 1978 (Box 69)
  - White, Milton, 1977 (Box 69)
  - White, Paul David, 1977 (Box 69)
  - Whiting, Bernard F., 1982-1985 (Box 69)
    Hawking, Stephen (1982)
  - Whitney, Hassler, 1978 (Box 69)
  - Wickes, William C., 1976-1981 (Box 69)
  - Wightman, Arthur S., 1982 (Box 69)
  - Wigner, Eugene P., 1977-1985 (Box 69)
    Wheeler, Janette (1985); Wigner, Pat (1985). -- See also Series II: Dyson, Freeman J.; Melvin, Mael A.; Nobel Conference (17th: St. Peter, Minnesota)
  - Wilczek, F., 1982 (Box 69)
  - Wildermuth, K., 1978 (Box 69)
  - Wilets, Lawrence, 1985-1986 (Box 69)
  - John Wiley and Sons, Inc., 1983 (Box 69)
  - Wilkins, Daniel, 1978 (Box 69)
  - Wilkinson, David T., 1977-1985 (Box 69)
    Williams, Thomas E., Jr.
  - Wilkinson, Denys, 1985 (Box 69)
  - Will, Clifford M., 1979-1980 (Box 69)
    -- See also Series II: Sakharov, Andrei (1986)
  - Willenbrock, Scott S. D., 1980-1981 (Box 69)
  - Williams, Dudley, 1982 (Box 69)
  - Williams, Prescott H., Jr., 1982 (Box 69)
  - Williams, Roger J., 1979-1984 (Box 69)
  - Williams, Ruth M., 1977 (Box 69)
  - Williamson, Frank, Jr., 1985-1986 (Box 69)
  - Willmes, Henry, 1976 (Box 69)
  - Wills, Derek, 1987 (Box 69)
  - Wilmer, Harry A., 1986 (Box 69)
  - Wilson, David L., 1979 (Box 69)
  - Wilson, Kenneth G., 1983 (Box 69)
  - Wilson, [Richard], 1977 (Box 69)
  - Wilson, Robert R., 1977, 1983 (Box 69)
    -- See also Series II: Union of Concerned Scientists
  - Wilson, W. O., 1977 (Box 69)
  - Winckler, John R[andolph], 1978 (Box 69)
  - Winfrey, Dorman H., 1986 (Box 69)
  - Wing, Lucila L., 1980-1986 (Box 69)
  - Winter, Norbert J., 1980 (Box 69)
  - Winters, Robert A., 1978-1979 (Box 69)
  - Wissenschaftliche Buchgesellschaft, 1978 (Box 69)
  - Witt, Georgia S., 1977-1979 (Box 69)
  - Witten, Edward, 1981 (Box 69)
  - Witten, Louis, 1977 (Box 69)
    -- See also Series II: Physics Today
  - Wolf, C., 1984-1986 (Box 70)
  - Wolfram, Stephen, 1981-1983 (Box 70)
  - Wolman, Abel, 1976-1982 (Box 70)
    Hollander, Walter, Jr.
  - Wong, Cheuk-Yin (Felix), 1977-1988 (Box 70)
  - Wood, Lowell, 1984 (Box 70)
  - Woodard, Richard P., 1982-1984 (Box 70)
  - Woodhouse, John C[rawford], 1980 (Box 70)
    Trabant, E. A.
  - Woodhouse, Nicholas, 1976-1977 (Box 70)
  - Woodson, H. H., 1977, 1986 (Box 70)
    Leveritt, Miles
  - Woolf, Harry, 1976-1981 (Box 70)
    Institute for Advanced Study
  - Wootters, William Kent, 1978-1986 (Box 70)
  - Worden, Sam P., 1982-1987 (Box 70)
    Hammer, Sigmund (1987); Worden, Helen. -- See also Series II: Penrose, Roger
  - Workshop on Quantum Noise in Macroscopic Systems, 1984 (Box 70)
  - World Book-Childcraft International, Inc., 1979-1983 (Box 70)
    Tressler, Arthur G.
  - World Congress of Philosophy, 1976 (Box 70)
  - World Organisation of Theological Relativity, Atomic Physics, and Molecular Biology, 1981 (Box 70)
  - World Scientific Publishing Co., 1986-1987 (Box 70)
  - Worthen, Deuard V., 1979-1985 (Box 70)
  - Wu, C. S., 1977 (Box 70)
  - Wu, H., 1977 (Box 70)
  - Wu, Zhong Chao, 1983-1985 (Box 70)
  - Wyllys, Ronald E., 1984-1986 (Box 70)
    American Libraries; Library Journal
  - Yahil, Amos, 1977 (Box 70)
  - Yajnik, Urgit A., 1981-1986 (Box 70)
  - Yanase, Michael M., 1980-1981 (Box 70)
  - Yang, Chen Ning, 1976, 1981 (Box 70)
  - Yasskin, Philip B., 1978-1980 (Box 70)
  - York, James W., Jr., 1976-1988 (Box 70)
  - Young, Arthur, 1977 (Box 70)
  - Young, Roberta E., 1982-1984 (Box 70)
  - Yourgrau, Wolfgang, 1976-1978 (Box 70)
  - Yuille, Alan L., 1979 (Box 70)
  - Yukawa, Hideki, 1981 (Box 70)
    American Philosophical Society; Sugimoto, Kenji
  - Zaini, Maria, 1983-1984 (Box 70)
  - Zambon, Zoila, 1980-1981 (Box 70)
    Genova, Alberto; Kaufmann, William
  - Zamorano, Nelson Arturo, 1977-1979 (Box 70)
  - Zee, Anthony, 1983-1986 (Box 70)
  - Zeh, H. Dieter, 1979-1982 (Box 70)
  - Zeilik, Michael, 1977-1978 (Box 70)
  - Zel'dovich, Ya. B., 1976-1986 (Box 70)
    Novikov, I. D.
  - Zerilli, Frank J., 1979 (Box 70)
  - Zhang, Tian-Rong, 1981-1988 (Box 71)
  - Zhang, Zhen-Jiu, 1981-1983 (Box 71)
  - Zhu, Shi-Chang, 1981-1982 (Box 71)
  - Zichichi, Antonino, 1977-1984, n.d. (Box OS1, Box 71)
    -- See also Series II: Weisskopf, Victor. -- See also: Oversized
  - Znajek, Roman L., 1978-1980 (Box 71)
  - Zurek, Wojciech H., 1977-1987; 2.0 folders (Box 71)
    George Mason University (1986); Schramm, David N. (1987); Smoluchowski, Roman (1981). -- See also Series II: Sigma Xi
    - Folder #1, 1977-1982 (Box 71)
    - Folder #2, 1983-1987 (Box 71)
  - Zuse, Konrad, 1981 (Box 71)
  - Zycinski, Joseph M., 1983-1984 (Box 71)
- III. Subject Files, 1909-1990 (Box 72-76, Volume 6-7)
  Contains material most often Wheeler used as research for papers, talks, and lectures. Some Subject Files contain works-in-progress and collaborations with other physicists. Materials in Series III were accessioned prior to 1994.
  - American Physical Society. Publications Committee, 1967 (Box 72)
    -- See also Series II: Kittel, C. (26 Jan. 1967)
  - Antiballistic Missile Citations, 1969, n.d. (Box 72)
  - Battelle-Northwest, 1967 (Box OS1)
  - Niels Bohr International Gold Medal, 1982; 1.0 Volume(s) (Volume 6)
  - Niels Bohr Material, 1928-1988, n.d.; 7.0 folders (Box 72)
    -- See also Series I: American Physical Society (1963); Becker, Bill (1954); Bohr, Aage (1963); Buchta, J.W. (1962-66); Gorter, [?] (1952); Hempel, C.G. (Peter) (1963); Moore, Ruth (1964); Nelson's Encyclopedia (1945-46); Pais, Abraham (1947); Perk, Susanne (Mrs. George D. (1952); Petersen, Aage (1963); Rosenfeld, L[eon] (1963); Williams, Dudley (1962).
    --See also Series II: American Institute of Physics (1982-83); Blaedel, Niels (1985); Bohr, Aage (1981, 1985); Bohr, Margarethe (1981, 1984); Casimir, H.B.G. (1985); Feynman, Richard P. (1977); French, Tony (1985); Frombold, Lothar ([1985]); Hehl, Friedrich W. (1985); Magnusson, Magnus (1981); Niels Bohr Institute (1982, 1984); Pais, Abraham ([1990]); Patzer, Christine (1985); Peierls, Rudolf (1980, 1982); Plesset, Milton S. (1982); Rudinger, Erik (1988); Smithsonian News Service (1985); Stuewer, Roger H. (1984); White, Milton (1977).
    - Folder #1, 1928-1957 (Box 72)
    - Folder #2, 1957-1963 (Box 72)
    - Folder #3, 1963-[1977] (Box 72)
    - Folder #4, 1978-1984 (Box 72)
    - Folder #5, [1985]-1988 (Box 72)
    - Folders #6-7, n.d.; 2.0 folders (Box 72)
  - California Institute of Technology. Visiting Committee for the Division of Physics, Mathematics and Astronomy, 1971 (Box 72)
  - Causality and Dispersion Theory, 1952-1958, n.d. (Box 72)
    Toll, John S.
  - Clippings, 1957-1978 (Box 72)
  - Conference on Physics (Pocono Manor, Pennsylvania), 1948 (Box 72)
  - Consciousness, 1973-1976 (Box 72)
  - Copyrights, 1978-1985 (Box 72)
  - Cosmology Papers, 1954-1970 (Box 72)
  - Double-ended Statistics, 1971-1980 (Box OS1, Box 73)
    -- See also Series I: Gal-Or, Benjamin (26 Mar. 1973); Partridge, R. Bruce (11 Sep. 1972); Schulman, Lawrence S. (16 Oct. 1976). -- See also Series VII: Double-ended Statistics. -- See also: Oversized
  - Albert Einstein Material, 1941-1990, n.d.; 4.0 folders (Box 73)
    -- See also Series I: Balaban, Miriam (1973); Bergmann, Peter (1971); Bork, Alfred M. (1975); Einstein, Albert (1924-1925, 1953); Einstein Papers (1971-1976); Gowing, Margaret (1974); Kuhn, Thomas S. (1973); Miller, Arthur I. (1972); National Academy of Sciences (1971); Ne'eman, Yuval (1973); Sargent, R. S. (1975); Schumacher, [D.L.] (1973); Segre, Emilio (1973).
    -- See also Series II: Aichelburg, P. (1977); American Institute of Physics (1979); American Philosophical Society (1979, 1982); Banks, Leslie (1987); Bauer, Henry H. (1983); Block, Edward M. (1979); Brown, Salley (1978); Crelinsten, Jeffrey (1981); E.I. du Pont de Nemours and Co. (1977); Einstein Papers (1976-1985); Elkana, Yehuda (1979); Elton, Lewis (1986); Gerwin, Robert (1979); Goldhaber, Gerson (1981); Greenberg, [Oscar] Wallace (1977); Hoffman, Banesh (1979, 1981); Holton, Gerald (1981); International Commission on Physics Education (1977); Kemper, William (1986); [Klein], Martin (1979); Luscher, E. (1979); McGraw, Harold W., Jr. (1982); Mark Twain Journal (1978); National Academy of Sciences (1978); National Science Foundation (1982); Obregon, [Octavio] (1979); Physics Today (1979); Physikalische Blatter (1978-1979); Pyenson, Lewis (1980-1981); Reid, Constance (1979); Resnick, Robert (1983); Sanchez-Ron, J.M. (1978); Siegfried, Tom and Chris (1978); Stoller, Lincoln (1978); Szebehely, Victor (1981); Teitelboim, Claudio (1979); University of Texas. Humanities Research Center (1979); von Koller, Otto (1979); Weart, Spencer (1975); Wellner, Marcel (1977).
    - Folder #1, 1941-1973 (Box 73)
    - Folder #2, 1974-1979 (Box 73)
    - Folder #3, 1979-1981 (Box 73)
    - Folder #4, 1982-1990, n.d. (Box 73)
  - Albert Einstein Publications, 1909-1985 (Box 73)
  - Einstein Statue, 1978-1979; 1.0 Volume(s) (Volume 7)
  - Elementary Particle Decay and Reactions (Box 73)
  - Energy. Material on the Concept of, 1967-1973 (Box 73)
    "16 1/2 Energy" on original folder. -- See also Series IV: "The End of Time"; "Our Changing View of Space"
  - Extrasensory Perception, Dowsing Materials, 1969-1990; 5.0 folders (Box 73-74)
    Alcock, James E. (1987); American Association for the Advancement of Science (1978-79); American Philosophical Society (1979); ASTOP, the Press: Newsletter of the Austin Society to Oppose Pseudoscience; Bartell, L.S. (1979); Boulding, Kenneth (1979); Brown, T. Townsend (1980); Chauvin, Andre (1978); Clark, Eloise E. (1979); Cohen, Mortimer T. (1979); Costa de Beauregard, Olivier (1980); Cummings, Martin M. (1979); David, Edward E., Jr. (1979); Dreiske, Paul C. (1980); Einhorn, Ira (1980); Faris, Robert E.L. (1979); Fife, Samuel T. (1980); Fox, Renee C. (1979); Friedman, Stanley M. (1979); Gardner, Martin (1980); Golden, William T. (1979); Graham, Lee M. (1981); Hansel, C.E.M. (1980); Harrison, Anna J. (1979); Holloman, Gina (1979); Hynek, J. Allen ([1980]); Isthmus Institute (1985); Jahn, Robert G. (1978); Jobes, Stanley (1979); Josephson, Brian D. (1980); Kane, Gordon (1979); Kienle, Edward C. (1980); Klachan, Pavel Peter (1985); McCormack, Mike (1979); McMahan, Elizabeth A. (1986); Maharishi International University (1979); Mattuck, Richard D. (1980); Meyers, David G. (1979); Mills, Kerry E. (1980); Morris, Robert L. (1987); Mosteller, Frederick (1979); New York Review of Books (1979-80); Osborne, Charles F. (1979); Peterson, Russell W. (1979); Phillips, Peter R. (1979); Powell, George D. (1980); Princeton Alumni Weekly (1979); Princeton University Press (1973-74); Rawlins, Dennis (1979); Rhine, J.B. (1979); Sawhill, John C. (1979); Schawalow, Arthur L. (1979); Science (1979); Sears, John E.J. (1979); Sheinmel, Joel (1988); Simon Fraser University (1979); Sineno, Joseph E. (1980); The Skeptical Inquirer (1980); Thompson, Howard E., Jr. (1980); Treiman, Sam (1988); Turnquist, Gary (1981); Vaughan, Alan (1979); Walker, Evan Harris (1980); Winthrop, John T. (1979); Worley, Donald L. (1980); Yang, Chen Ning (1979); Zetetic Scholar (1980).
    - Folder #1, 1969-1979 (Box 73)
    - Folder #2, 1979 (Box 74)
    - Folder #3, 1980 (Box 74)
    - Folder #4, 1980-1981 (Box 74)
    - Folder #5, 1982-1988 (Box 74)
  - Mitchell Feigenbaum and Disorder, 1967-1984 (Box 74)
  - Enrico Fermi Award, 1968 (Box 74)
    -- See also Series I: Fermi Award, Letters of Congratulations
  - Feynman's Sum Over Histories, 1982 (Box 74)
  - Fulbright Application, 1955 (Box 74)
  - Gravitational Radiation, 1954-1977, n.d. (Box 74)
    Putnam, [Peter]. -- See also Series I: Weber, Joseph (1956)
  - Half-Retarded, Half-Advanced Potentials, 1978-1984, n.d. (Box 74)
  - History and Philosophy of Science, 1957-1980 (Box OS1, Box 74)
    -- See also Series I: Moore, Ruth (9 Mar. 1966); Pauli, W[olfgang] (1926); Weyl, Jo[seph] (18 Jun. 1965). -- See also Series II: International Symposium on the History of Particle Physics (20 Mar. 1980). -- See also Oversized
  - Inflationary Universe, 1982-1983 (Box 75)
  - International Conference on Neutron Interactions with Nuclei, n.d. (Box 75)
  - International Conference on the Neutron Interactions with the Nucleus, 1957 (Box 75)
  - Language, 1950-1985 (Box 75)
  - Lecomte du Nouy Award, 1954-1965 (Box 75)
    -- See also Series I: The Lecomte du Nouy Award
  - Mailing List for Reprints, etc., 1973-1980, n.d. (Box 75)
    "Einstein's Vision"; "From Relativity to Mutability"
  - Measurement of Space and Time, [1960]-1971 (Box 75)
    -- See also Series I: Duncombe, R.L. (1970); Hudson, George E. (1967, 1971); Massachusetts Institute of Technology (1970); U.S. Department of Commerce, National Bureau of Standards (1971)
  - Moon, Origin of the, 1959-1971, 1982 (Box 75)
    Brush, Stephen G.; Bussard, R[obert] W.
  - National Academy of Sciences. National Research Council, 1960 (Box 75)
  - National Research Council. Office of Scientific Personnel, 1956-1957 (Box 75)
  - New Mexico Map, 1949 (Box OS1)
    Oversized map of New Mexico and the city of Santa Fe
  - Organisation for European Economic Cooperation, 1959 (Box 75)
  - Princeton University. Physics Department Journal Club, 1975-1976 (Box 75)
  - Quantum Geometrodynamics, 1966-1967 (Box 75)
  - Quantum Theory Conference (Texas), 1982 (Box 75)
  - Rockefeller Institute, n.d. (Box OS1)
  - Science Education and Scientific Personnel, 1930-1962, n.d.; 3.0 folders (Box 75, Box OS1)
    -- See also Series I: National Science Foundation. -- See also Oversized
    - Folder #1, 1930-1956 (Box 75)
    - Folder #2, 1957-1958 (Box 75)
    - Folder #3, 1959-1962, n.d. (Box 75)
  - Special Relativity, 1950-1967 (Box 76)
    Thorne, Kip S. (1966-1967)
  - Texas Symposium on Relativistic Astrophysics, 1974 (Box 76)
  - Time-Relativity and Quantization References, 1956-1981 (Box 76)
  - United States Atomic Energy Commission, 1960 (Box 76)
  - University of Newcastle Upon Tyne. Honorary Degree, 1983 (Box 76)
  - University of Texas. Center for Theoretical Physics. Conference, 1980-1981 (Box 76)
    For photographs, see Series VII: University of Texas. Center for Theoretical Physics. Conference
  - University of Texas. Five-Year Plan for Science, 1984 (Box 76)
  - University of Texas at Austin, 1976-1987, n.d. (Box 76)
    Santa Rita [Oil Well]. -- See also Series VII: University of Texas at Austin
- IIIA. Subject Files, 1914-2006 (Box 165-176, Volume 8-11)
  Contains material most often Wheeler used as research for papers, talks, and lectures. Some Subject Files contain works-in-progress and collaborations with other physicists. Materials in Series IIIA were accessioned in 1994 and later years.
  - Acapulco Effect, 1979-1980 (Box 165)
  - America, n.d. (Box 165)
  - Ancient History, 1921-1996 (Box 165)
  - Astrophysics, 1979-1984 (Box 165)
  - Atomic Energy, Atomic Weapons, 1945-1985 (Box 165)
    Clippings
  - Black Hole Chemical Potential, 1958-1978 (Box 165)
  - Bohr, Niels Henrik, 1885-1961, 1939-1978; 2.0 folders (Box 165)
    - Folder #1, 1939-1957 (Box 165)
    - Folder #2, 1962-1978 (Box 165)
  - Chemical Atom, 1976 (Box 165)
  - China, 1996-1997 (Box 165)
  - Clippings, [1925]-2000; 5.0 folders (Box OS1, Box 166)
    Copies of oversized materials have been placed in the regular-sized folders.
    - Folder #1, [1925]-1959 (Box 166)
    - Folder #2, 1960-1979 (Box 166)
    - Folder #3, 1980-2000 (Box 166)
    - Folder #4, 1953-1997 (Box 166)
    - Folder #5, 1958-1996 (Box 166)
  - Convair Limited War Panel, 1954-1971; 9.0 folders (Box 166-167)
    - Folder #1. [Clippings, correspondence, notes on ARPA, NDL, IDA, NPAC], 1958-1959 (Box 166)
      Kissinger, Henry, 1923-
    - Folder #2. [Clippings, correspondence, notes on ARPA, NDL, IDA, NPAC], 1954-1958 (Box 166)
      Jackson, Henry M., (Henry Martin), 1912-1983
    - Folder #3. [Clippings, correspondence, notes on ARPA, NDL, IDA, NPAC], 1959 (Box 166)
    - Folder #4. [Clippings, correspondence, notes on ARPA, NDL, IDA, NPAC], 1959 (Box 166)
    - Folder #5. [Notes and Draft Manuscript on Limited War], 1959 (Box 167)
    - Folder #6. A Doctrine for Limited War [Original], 1959 (Box 167)
    - Folder #7. Convair Study of Limited War: Summary of Military and Technical Aspects. A Doctrine For Limited War [Copy], 1959 (Box 167)
    - Folder #8. For ABM Notebook, 1969 (Box 167)
    - Folder #9. United States Foreign Policy For the 1970's: Building For Peace. Nixon's Report to Congress. 25 February 1971 (Box 167)
  - Defense Studies, 1950-1976; 2.0 folders (Box 167)
    - Folder #1, 1950-1969 (Box 167)
    - Folder #2, 1969-1976 (Box 167)
  - Einstein, Albert, 1879-1955, 1979-1996; 2.0 folders (Box 167-168)
  - Einstein Stamp, 1966 (Box 168)
  - Elan and Morale, 1960-1988; 3.0 folders (Box 168)
    - Folder #1, 1960-1979 (Box 168)
    - Folder #2, 1980-1981 (Box 168)
    - Folder #3, 1982-1988 (Box 168)
  - Electron Leakage, 1965-1972 (Box 168)
  - Enoch Pratt Library, 1980-2003, n.d. (Box 168)
  - Evolution, 1958-1980 (Box 168)
  - Feynman, Richard P. (Richard Phillips), 1918-1988, 1988-1995 (Box 169)
  - Fitch, Val L., 1923-, 1991-1997 (Box 169)
  - Fork, 1959-1982 (Box 169)
  - Franz Gross. Seeing Stars Double, 1959-1977 (Box 169)
  - Fuchs, Klaus, 1950 (Box 169)
  - Future of Physics, 1967-1983; 3.0 folders (Box 169)
    - Folder #1, 1967-1975 (Box 169)
    - Folder #2, 1976 (Box 169)
    - Folder #3, 1977-1983 (Box 169)
  - General Relativity, 1986 (Box 169)
  - Gravitational Collapse, Supernovae, 1964-1977; 3.0 folders (Box 169-170)
    - Folder #1, 1964-1974 (Box 169)
    - Folder #2, 1964-1974 (Box 170)
    - Folder #3, 1965-1977 (Box 170)
  - Great Truth, 1972 (Box 170)
  - Groups Hide Physics, 1974 (Box 170)
  - Havel, Vaclav, 1995 (Box 170)
  - Hawking, S. W. (Stephen W.), 1988-1992 (Box 170)
  - Herzfeld, Karl F. (Karl Ferdinand), 1892-1978, 1965-1988; 5.0 folders (Box 170-171)
    - Folder #1, 1965-1971 (Box 170)
    - Folder #2, 1971 (Box 170)
    - Folder #3, 1971 (Box 171)
    - Folder #4, 1971 (Box 171)
    - Folder #5, 1975-1988 (Box 171)
  - History of Nuclear Physics, 1967-1976 (Box 171)
  - History and Philosophy of Science, 1947-1974; 3.0 folders (Box 171)
    - Folder #1, 1947-1969 (Box 171)
    - Folder #2, 1965-1969 (Box 171)
    - Folder #3, 1970-1974 (Box 171)
  - Information and Dimensionality, 1962-1980 (Box 172)
  - Initial Value Problem, 1957-1988 (Box 172)
  - InterAmerican Undergraduate Conference in Theoretical Physics (2nd: Austin, TX: 1978), 1.0 Volume(s) (Volume 8)
  - InterAmerican Undergraduate Conference in Theoretical Physics (3th: 1979: Austin: Texas), 1.0 Volume(s) (Volume 9)